여기요
Hey!
여기요, 이쪽
Hey! Over here!
Over this way!
제가 신고했어요, 저기있어요.
I'm the one who called!
He's right over there!
♪ NCIS 12x14 ♪
Cadence
Original Air Date on February 10, 2015
??NCIS 12x14 ??/font>
Cadence
Original Air Date on February 10, 2015
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
발로 만든 자막입니다. 이해하세요.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
?? ??
도착했네
Here we are.
둘다 있을거라고 했지?
Told you they'd be here.
모두 주목, 제이크 말로이가 왔네요
Hey, look, everybody!
It's Jake Malloy!
비숍의 반쪽
The yin to Bishop's yang.
무슨일예요? NSA의 자유복 출근 화요일?
Hey, what is it,
Casual Tuesday at NSA?
YMCA에서 커플요가 했어요
Couples yoga at the YMCA.
Mm-hmm.
늦어서, 여기서 갈아입으려고요
It ran late.
We're changing here.
요즘들어 둘이 커플로 바쁘네요
You guys have been doing
a lot of couples classes lately.
행복한 결혼생활을 위해 노력하는 거죠
Always working
to improve our marriage.
근데, 별로예요
And it sucks.
같이 하는거요. 우리 결혼 말고..
The classes. Not our marriage.
지난 주엔,
Last week, it was...
커플맛사지 했어요
couples massage.
맞아, 좀 징그러웠지
Yeah, that was
just creepy.
응, 그래서 오늘 아침부터는
Yeah. So after this morning,
잠시 떨어져있기로 했어요
we decided
we are taking a break.
아, 커플로 하는거요
From, uh, the classes.
헤어지는게 아니라..
Not each other.
그래서 엘리가 멋진 아이디어를 냈는데..
And then Ellie had
a brilliant idea...
커플 활동에 대한 해결방안을 찾았다니 기쁜데 말야,
I'm glad that you guys
are figuring all this
couple stuff out,
근데, 난 좀 바빠서..
but if you'll
excuse me...
엘리의 아이디어가 궁금하지 않아요?
Don't you want
to hear what the idea was?
미스터리는 궁금한 체로 두는게 더 좋다는거 아나?
You know, isn't the mystery
of not knowing more exciting?
엘리, 난 궁금해.
Ellie, I would love to hear
그만해라, 맥기
what your idea was.
Don't you dare, McGee.
난 진지해요, 토니
I'm being courteous, Tony.
이건 함정야, 팀
It's a trap, Tim.
우리랑 저녁식사 같이해요
We want to take you to dinner.
뭔 속셈이야?
속셈은요. 그냥 초대죠.
What's the catch?
No catch. Our treat.
우리가 NSA에서 근무할땐, 같은 동료들 하고 일했어요
At NSA,
we had the same colleagues.
근데, 제이크가 당신들에 대해 아는게 없더라구요
But Jake doesn't really know
you guys.
그래서 나와 맥기를
So you want to take
me and McGee
아무조건없이 저녁식사에 초대하겠다?
to dinner,
no strings attached.
깁스씨도.
깁스라고?
And Gibbs.
이봐요들.
Well, there you go.
잘모르는 모양인데,
Don't know if you've noticed,
우리가 사랑하고 무서워하는 깁스아저씨는
but the boss
hasn't been the fun,
사석에선 전혀 재밌지 않다고..
social Gibbs
that we all love and fear.
네, 물론, 요새들어 고민이 많은건 알아요
Yeah, well, he has had
a lot on his mind lately.
그 정도 말로는 약과지
That's an understatement.
허락하실리도 없을테고..
Doesn't matter though-- there is
no way he's gonna say yes.
이미 약속했다
Already have.
자네들도 꼭 오시게..
Expecting you to be there.
당연히 갑니다, 보스
저녁식사가 기대됩니다, 보스
I'll have bells on, boss.
I love dinner, boss.
좋아, 자세한 얘기는 나중에 하고.. 가자
Good. We'll go over the
details later. Come on.
그윈스 폴에서 해병의 사체가 발견됐다
Got a dead Marine
in Gwynns Falls.
잠깐 옷 좀 갈아입어도 돼죠?
Can I have a minute to change?
차에서 갈아입어야 겠네
I'll change in the car.
이따봐
Bye.
잠깐,
Wait.
차에서 뭘한다구?
You'll what?
피해자는 존 왈리스 이병, 19세.
The victim
is Private John Wallis.
19 years old.
오늘 아침 일찍, 여행자들이 발견해서
주경찰에 신고했습니다.
State troopers were
alerted early this morning
when a hiker
discovered the body.
경찰이 피해자의 시계와
Police found Wallis's watch,
현금 300달러가 든 지갑을 발견했고, 핸드폰은 없었네요
wallet, and $300 cash,
but no cell phone.
냉랭한 아침공기와 험난한 지형들이,
Nothing like
the frigid morning air
and treacherous terrain
for me to regret giving
Mr. Palmer paternity leave.
팔머군한테 준 육아휴가를 후회스럽게 만드는구만
잘하신거예요, 덕.
No good deed, Duck.
누가 우릴 부르신 건가?
Yeah.
Who have we got here?
오, 이런...
Oh, man...
피를 많이 흘렸네요
Quite a blood-letting.
토니, 여기 좀 도와주겠나?
Tony, would you, uh,
help me? Just...
돌려보세. 그래.
roll him up....
here, you see?
피투성이구만
Our victim is covered in blood.
많은 자상 때문인게 분명하군
Apparently the result
of multiple wounds.
사체 주변이나 아래에는 혈흔이 없구만
And yet there's no blood
underneath or around him.
살해된 다음 유기된 거네요
So Wallis was dumped here
after he was killed.
혈흔이 이쪽으로 나 있군
Blood trail leads this way.
살해 현장은 숲 안쪽이라 생각하시는군요?
You think the initial crime
scene is deeper in the woods?
"Verum,
Animus, Officium."
진실, 용기, 의무
Truth, Valor, Duty.
라틴어를 하는진 몰랐네, 토니
I didn't know
you spoke Latin, Tony.
그 단어들을 아는거죠
Well, I know those words.
레밍턴 군사학교의 모토 거든요
That's the motto of
the Remington Military Academy.
제가 갔었던 마지막 전문학교예요
It's the last prep school
I ever went to.
왈리스도 거기 출신인가 봅니다
I guess Wallis went there, too.
제복을 입은 토니라.. 꼭 보고 싶네요
Tony in a uniform.
I'd pay to see that.
손에 뭔가 쥐고 있네요, 보스
He's got something
in his hand here, boss.
사진 같은데..
Looks like a photo.
알아볼 순 없네요
I can't make it out.
뭔진 몰라도, 마지막까지 쥐고 있었군
Whatever it is,
he was holding on for dear life.
이거 보여? 살인자가 왈리스의 시체를
See this? Killer dragged
이리로 옮긴거군
Wallis's body from
somewhere down here.
Huh.
근데, 군사학교란 말이죠?
So, military school, huh?
그래, 맞아.
So, yeah.
제복, PT, 훈련..
Uniforms, PT, drills...
그래, 모두 군사학교에서 하는 것들이지, 맞아..
Those are all things that
happen at military school, yes.
어땠어요?
선배들의 천국이였어,
How'd you end up there?
It was Senior's Hail Mary,
삐뚤어지지 않기 위해 노력했지,
4년동안 6개 기숙학교를 거친 후 였거든..
trying to straighten me out
after six boarding schools
in four years.
흠
Huh.
상상하던 청소년 시절의 토니와 비슷하네요
It just doesn't really jibe with
my mental picture of Tony at 17.
거창한 의식이나 제복따윈 싫어했을거구요
You must have hated it,
the pomp and circumstance.
이것 좀 봐
Hey, look at this.
방수포처럼 보이는걸
This looks like some kind
of tarp.
시체를 싸는데 사용했을거야
Might've been used
to wrap the body up.
여기 타이어 자국이 잇네요
I got tire tracks over here.
타이어 자국이라
Tire tracks.
범인은 이쪽 진입로로 접근해서
So let's say the killer
used this access road,
시체를 옮긴 거군
dragged the body up
to where we found it...
자, 슬슬, 시작해 봅시다.
Set a fire to burn the evidence.
학창시절, 라틴어 과목이
Well, I thoroughly enjoyed
정말 즐거웠다네
my Latin classes in school.
카이사르의 갈리아 전기 제5권을 번역했지
Translating
Caesar's Gallic Wars, Book 5.
놀라운 일이야
It's amazing.
문명이란 이름으로 2000년이 흘렀지만
2,000 years
of so-called civilization
우린 아직도 똑같은 전쟁을 하고 있다네
and we're still fighting
the same wars.
뭐 좀 나온거 있어요, 덕?
What do you got
for me, Duck?
이 젊은이는 스무번이나 찔렸다네
Well, young Private Wallis
was stabbed 20 times.
대부분의 성처들이 상체쪽에 몰려있고,
Most of the wounds
are in the upper abdomen,
비장과 간을 찢어놨지
damaging his
spleen and liver.
그리고, 목에 있는 이 상처가
However,
it's this cut to his neck
경동맥을 잘라 대량의 출혈을 야기했네
that severed the carotid artery
and caused all that...
dramatic bleeding.
무기는?
칼.
Weapon?
Weapon. A knife.
곧은 날, 6인치 정도.
Straight-edged.
Six inches.
여기 두 상처에 독특한 흔적을 남겼어
It left a distinctive mark
on two of the wounds.
칼자루가 찍힌걸수도 있고..
It could be an imprint
of the hilt.
애비가 자세히 살펴보고 있네
Abby's looking into it.
다른건요?
여깄네.
Anything else?
Well, no.
이게 좀 이상한건데..
And that's what's strange.
손과 손가락에 멍든 흔적이나 상처가 없다네
There's no bruised knuckles or
cuts on his hands and fingers.
대항하지 못했네요
He didn't put up a fight.
Peculiar for a Marine
인간 병기로 단련된 해병에게
that's trained
as a lethal weapon.
이런 상처를 입힐 정도로
But someone was able
to get close enough to him
가까이 갈 수 있는 누군가 있었단 거네
to cause all these wounds.
생각치도 못했을 겁니다.
He was taken by surprise.
이런 경우 대부분 면식범의 소행이지
And most likely
by someone he knew.
왈리스는 레밍턴 군사학교의 장학생이였습니다.
Private Wallis was
a scholarship student
at Remington
Military Academy.
우등생이였고, 지난 봄 졸업,
Top of his class. He joined
the Marine Corps just three days
3일 후 해병대에 입대했습니다
after he graduated
last spring.
보병 훈련소에서도
Where he also excelled.
동기 중에 일등이였네요
Top of his class
in the school of infantry.
제22 해병원정대 소속으로,
His unit was part
of the 22nd MEU,
전함 에거튼 호를 타고 노포크에서 출항했습니다.
set to deploy on the
USS Edgerton out of Norfolk.
5일전, 전화 한통을 받았구요,
Five days ago, he received
a call to his cell phone.
계좌 잔액 1,500달러를 전부 인출 후 탈영,
Then he emptied
his bank account--
1,500 bucks--
and went UA.
이후 신용카드나 핸드폰은 사용하지 않았어요
Didn't use his credit
cards or cell phone.
잠수탄거죠.
잠수타기 전에..
- Just vanished.
- But what we do have
마지막으로 받은 전화를 추적해보니
is the last call
he received
before he went quiet.
Traced the phone number
레밍턴 군사학교 전화번호였어요
back to the Remington
Military Academy.
기숙사 내부 전화라서
It's a house phone
in one of the dorms.
백여명의 후보생들이 사용하고 있습니다
Any one of 100 cadets
could have placed that call.
뭐 어쨌든 , 왈리스는 전화받고
But whatever was said,
Wallis went UA
바로 탈영한거네요
immediately afterwards.
좋아, 학교로 가봐
Okay. Go to the school.
누가 건 전화인지 알아야 겠어
I want to know
who made the call.
아, 저기..
Uh... uh...
둘다 갈 필요가 있을까요? 그러니까,
Do both of us really need
to go there? I mean,
요원 두명이 모두 로드 아일랜드까지 갈 필요가 있을까요?
do we really need two agents to
go all the way to Rhode Island?
모교 방문에 무슨 문제있나, 디노조?
Is there a problem, DiNozzo,
with you going back
to your Alma mater?
좋아, 이리와봐, 얘기 좀 해보자, 음
Well, hey, let us go talk
about it. Let's-let's, uh...
커피라도 한잔 하면서.. 해결해보자구..
let's have a cup of coffee.
Let's... hash it out.
그럴 것 까진 없구요.. 그게..
I don't need to hash it out.
I just need to...
정신적인 준비가 좀 필요해서요..
prepare myself for
the psychological...
이봐,
Hey.
여섯시간 차타고, 호텔에서 하룻밤 자는건데,
You got six hours in a car,
you got one night
in a hotel room
정신적 준비가 필요하다 이거지?
to prepare psychologically.
잘해보세요, 겁쟁이 양반! (skippy)
Make it count, Skippy.
고마워요, 보스
Thank you, boss.
떠들시간 없어, 맥기
No time for chitchat, McGee.
엄마가 요리하느라 바쁘다구...
사건때문야, 애비.
Mama's cookin' on all six burners here.
Strictly business, Abby.
토니와 비숍이 사건현장에서 발견한
Just wondering if you found
anything useful off the ashes
잿더미에서 뭐가 나왔는지 궁금해서 말야.
Tony and Bishop found
near the crime scene.
눈물 나오고, 목 가렵게하는거 말고? 없어!
Other than watery eyes
and an itchy throat, nothing.
미리 말해두는데,
And before you say anything,
타이어 자국도 일치하는 걸 찾지 못했어
I haven't matched the tire
tracks from the crime scene.
살인무기에 대해서도 묻지마
And don't even ask
about the murder weapon.
칼로 찔린 모형하고 하루 죙일 씨름했어
I was planning on
stabbing dummies all day,
근데, 아무것도 모르겠어
but now I don't know.
애비..
Abby...
좀 도와줘도 될까?
I was gonna ask if I can help.
오.. 좋아, 괜찮은 생각야..
Oh... well, that's nice.
이리와서 혈흔 지우는거 좀 도와줘
Why don't you come over here and
help me get blood off this photo.
이게 신나지도, 재밌지도 않지만 말야
It's not glamorous
and it's not fun,
사진에 묻은 혈흔 지우는데는 젤 좋은 방법이지
but it's the best way
to get blood off a photo.
이게 오래 걸리면, 내일 밤은 빠질 수 있겠구나
Maybe if this takes long enough,
I can skip tomorrow night.
내일밤에 뭔일 있어?
What's tomorrow night?
맥기?
McGee?
알았어.
Okay.
제이크랑 비숍이 내일밤 저녁식사에 초대했거든
Jake and Bishop invited us
to dinner tomorrow night.
요원들끼리만 먹는 건가봐, 그러니까...
괜찮아, 맥기.
I think it's an agents-only thing, but...
Relax, McGee.
초대받지 못했다고 섭섭한건 아니지?
You're not upset
you weren't invited?
아냐, 왜 섭섭하겠어?
No. Why would I be?
버트와 난, 비숍과 제이크랑 많은 시간을 같이 보내
Burt and I hang out with
Bishop and Jake all the time.
커플로 여가활동도 같이 하는걸.
We even took a class together.
설마 커플 마사지는 아니겠지?
Please tell me
it wasn't couples massage.
마사지가 아니라 살짝 누르기야, 맥기
Dab, McGee. Dab.
애비가 사진을 깨끗하게 만들었네요
Abby was able to clear up the
photo found in Wallis's hand.
예쁘네요, 기지에서 근무하나?
Pretty girl.
Someone from the base?
해병대 군복은 아냐
Not a Marine uniform.
레밍턴 군사학교 교복이야
That's RMA.
왈리스의 급우일수도 있겠군
Maybe she's Wallis's classmate.
신원은 알 수 없데요
Abby wasn't able
to identify her.
좋아, 학교가면 알게 되겠지
Well, they'll know
at the school.
모교로 돌아가는게 내키지 않아요?
You feeling nervous to go back?
난 다 큰 어른이야, 비숍
I'm a grown man, Bishop.
그 정도론 흔들리지 않는다구
Takes a little bit more
than a visit to my old school
to make me nervous.
자, 디노조,
So, DiNozzo,
기차역까지 모시러 간 생도는 니가 처음이다
you may very well be the first
cadet to get limo service
from the train station.
아버님이 뭔가 손을 쓰셨나 보다
Guess your dad wields
some influence.
학교소개는 내일 정식으로 해줄께
We'll give you a
proper tour tomorrow.
다른 생도들처럼 헐 하우스를 사용할거야
You'll be in Hull House
with the rest of the seniors.
다왔다.
Here we are.
"총은 버려. 파이는 챙기고" (대부, 1972년작)
"Leave the gun.
Take the cannoli."
대부 몰라?
The Godfather?
이봐, 명작이라구.
Come on, kid, it's a classic.
교복, 운동복, 기본적인 세면도구는 니 방에 있다
Uniforms, PT gear and basic
toiletries are in your room.
사이즈가 맞을지 모르겠구나
We had to guess sizes.
여기다
This is you.
트레비스 펠프스가 니 룸메이트야
Your bunkmate's name
is Travis Phelps.
원래.. 첫날밤이 제일 힘든 법이다
Look... first night
is usually the hardest.
아래층에 있을테니까, 필요하면 날 불러라
If you need me,
I'm down the hall.
전 7살짜리 어린애가 아닙니다
I'm 17, not seven.
기숙사 생활은 예전에도 해봤구요
And this isn't my
first new dorm room,
new clothes and
new teachers.
그러니까 이제 그만하시죠, 아저씨
So back off, buddy, okay?
내이름은 아저씨가 아니다.
The name's not buddy.
테너 씨라고 불러
It's Mr. Tanner.
그리고, 지금부터 넌 디노조 생도다
And from now on
you are Cadet DiNozzo.
취침점호는 생략한다
Grab some rack time.
이게 누구야?
Can't believe my eyes.
못된 앤토니 디노조가 돌아왔구나
Anthony frickin' DiNozzo
back on my campus.
만나서 반갑다
I'm happy to see you.
반갑습니다, 코치님
Nice to see you, Coach.
제럴드라고 불러도 된다
Please, call me Gerald.
제럴드, 이쪽은 NCIS 특수요원 비숍입니다.
Gerald, this is
NCIS Special Agent Bishop.
아, NCIS..놀랍구나
Ah... NCIS.
Very impressive.
이놈을 자랑스럽게 여길 날이 언젠간 올줄 알았습니다
I always knew this one
would make me proud.
정말요?
물론이죠.
You did?
Yeah.
그게, 인사드리러 온건 아니구요
Well, we're not
here to reminisce.
물론이지.. 존 왈리스 때문에 왔다고..
Of course not. Uh, you're here
about John Wallis.
슬픈일이지.. 어떻게 도와주면 되겠니?
Tragic. How can I help?
아, 이 여자를 아시나요?
Uh, wondering if you
know this girl.
크리스틴 샌더스 군요
That's Christine Sanders.
가능한 빨리 그녀를 만났으면 합니다
We need to talk to her
as soon as possible.
그게 좀 힘들겠다
I'm afraid that's impossible.
왜요?
Why?
이미 고인이 됐거든요
Christine Sanders is dead.
크리스틴은 신입생이였어요
Christine was a junior.
열정적이였죠. 우등생 명단에도 올랐어요
A go-getter. She was
on the dean's list,
디노조 처럼.
just like DiNozzo.
최초의 여성 졸업생 대표가 될거라고 기대했었죠
And she was on track
to becoming our first
female valedictorian.
아, 잠시만요, 방금 뭐라고 하셨죠?
Uh... I'm sorry,
can we back up a second?
토니가 우등생이였다구요?
Did you say...
Tony made dean's list?
그는 모든 생도들의 모범이였습니다
He shaped into a model cadet.
집중 좀 합시다
Let's stay on point here.
크리스틴은 어떻게 된거죠?
What about Christine?
성적이 떨어지더군요.
Her grades
started slipping.
내성적으로 변하고..육상부도 그만두고..
She became withdrawn.
Quit the track team.
열흘후에, 그녀의 방에서 죽은 걸
Ten days ago,
the senior cadet
선임생도가 발견했어요
discovered her
in her room, dead.
약물과용이라더군요
She'd overdosed
on pills.
아무도 눈치채지 못했나요?
No one saw the signs?
우리 학생들의 절반정도가
Look, half the students
in our academy
문제를 일으켜서 여기 온거예요
are here because
they are troubled.
크리스틴도 방황하던 때가 있었구요
Even Christine had
her rough times.
그래서 여기로 온거죠
That's why she was here.
그들에게 새로운 기회를 주는게 우리의 역할입니다
We have built our reputation
on turning young lives around.
토니를 보세요
Just look at him.
존 왈리스는 어땠나요?
What about John Wallis?
오, 매우 훌륭한 학생이였지. 운동도 잘했고.
Oh, he's a great kid;
great athlete.
작년까지 선임생도였네
He was senior cadet
last year.
그 역시 우리의 기대를 모았지
We all saw
a bright future for him.
크리스튼과의 관계는요?
What was Christine's
relationship with him?
왈리스가 그녀의 직속상관이였어요
Wallis was her
commanding officer.
아, 그에게 배속된 40명의 생도중 하나였죠
Uh, she was one of 40
cadets under his care.
선생님, 그는 마지막까지
Come on, Coach.
그녀의 사진을 손에 꼭 쥔채 죽었습니다
He had her photo
in his hand when he died.
이 학교는 95년에 남녀공학이 됐고,
The school became coed in '95.
아직도 생도들 사이의 남녀 문제로
And honestly, we're
골치가 아픈게 사실이네
still navigating the raging
hormones on campus.
하지만, 명확한 규정이 있어
But there is
one clear rule:
생도들 사이의 연예는 절대로 용납되지 않는다네
Dating amongst the ranks
is strictly forbidden.
지난 며칠간 왈리스가 학교를 방문한적이 있나요?
00:14:09,065 -> 00:14:11,365
아, 내가 아는한 없네
Did Wallis come back
to campus in the last few days?
Uh, not that I know of.
아, 근데, 좀 혼란스러운데...
Look, I-I'm sorry,
I'm confused.
음.. 왈리스의 죽음이
Um, do you think
Wallis's death
크리스틴과 관계가 있다고 생각하나?
had something
to do with Christine?
크리스틴은 열흘전에 죽었어요
Christine died
ten days ago.
며칠후에, 왈리스는 그녀의 기숙사에서 전화한통을 받았구요
A few days later, Wallis
received a call from her dorm.
그 후에 탈영했죠
Then he went UA.
크리스틴이 이미 죽었던 거라면,
If Christine was already dead,
생도 중 누군가가 왈리스한테 전화한 겁니다
anyone on campus
could have called Wallis.
방해하려는 건 아니야, 앱스
Remind me never
to piss you off, Abbs.
좀 냅둬요, 깁스
Couldn't if you
tried, Gibbs.
지금 왈리스 이병을 죽이는 데 사용된
I'm just trying
to match the knife
칼을 찾고 있는데..
that was used to
kill private Wallis.
아직까진 운이 없네요
But no luck, so far.
좋아, 탈영 이후에 그의 행적을 추적해 보자구
Okay, let's track Wallis's
movements after he went UA.
핸드폰을 꺼놨어요.
그러면, 음
His cell phone's off.
Then, uh,
GPS의 램 어쩌구를 해킹해서,
can we hack into, uh,
his GPS RAM thingy
역추적하면 되지않나?
and back-trace
his memory deal?
음..
Um...
그게, 걔네들이 말예요, 깁스
None of those things are...
things, Gibbs.
서로 연결돼 있어서
And one of 'em's a band.
핸드폰을 꺼버리면
And when someone
turns their phone off,
어떻게 할 수가 없어요.
그러니까, 꺼졌다구요..
there's nothing you can do.
I mean, it's off.
그러니까..
그냥 껐다는 거니까..
Of course...
just because it's off
다시 켤 수도 있겠는 걸?..
doesn't mean I can't
turn it back on.
뭐?
It doesn't?
핸드폰 종류에 따라 다른데요,
Depending on what type
of phone Wallis had,
어쩌면 원격으로 켤 수도 있겠어요
I may be able to remotely
turn it back on.
그러면.. 되겠네
And, yes, then
우리가 핸드폰의 GPS 램 머시기를 해킹할 수 있겠네요.
we can hack into his GPS
thingy memory deal.
좋아.
Okay.
좋아, 해보자구
Okay, let's do it.
앱스..
Hey, Abs.
보스, 방금 뉴잉글랜드 전화카드와 통화했습니다
Boss, just got off the phone
with New England TeleCard.
뉴잉글랜드 전화카드?
What is New England TeleCard?
생도들에게 전화카드를 파는 회사예요
They provide calling cards
to the cadets at RMA.
왈리스가 탈영한 날, 전화한 생도의 이름을 알려줬어요
They were also able to give me
the name of the cadet
who called Wallis
the night he went UA.
루카스 크레이그 생도 랍니다
Caller was Cadet Lucas Craig.
디노조와 비숍에게 알려줘
Tell DiNozzo and Bishop.
됐어요.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
왈리스의 핸드폰을 켰어요
I turned Wallis's
phone back on.
위치를 추적해 볼께요
I'm tracing
its location now.
지금 있는 곳은...
It's at a residence
that belongs to...
프레드릭 캔토의 집이네요. 리치몬드, 버지니아.
Frederick Cantor;
Richmond, Virginia.
루카스 크래이그는 선임생도라네
Lucas Craig
is Senior Cadet.
그러니까, 학교에서 꽤 높은 위치에 있다는 거지
Means he's the highest-ranking
student on campus.
토니도 선임생도였어요?
Were you Senior Cadet, Tony?
아뇨, 나하고 농구 코트에서 뒹구느라 바빴답니다
No, he was too busy
shaking and baking on the
basketball court for me.
그래도, 학교 기수였어요
But he was a flag bearer.
뭐하고 있어?
What are you doing?
아, 맥기가 자세히 알려달라고 했거든요
Uh, McGee wants a detailed report.
Stop it.
냅둬요.
Hey.
Craig's overseeing
크레이그는 밖에서 훈련을 지휘하고 있어요
close-order drill outside.
곧 끝날 겁니다
He'll be done soon.
전 교수회의가 있어서..
Uh, I've got a
faculty meeting.
근처에 있을 거지?
Will you be around
afterwards?
바로 돌아가야 해서요..
Actually, we're
heading back to DC.
음, 그렇군. 나중에 보세.
Well, that's too bad.
I wanted to catch up.
반가웠어요
Pleasure.
만나서 정말 반가웠다
Really good to see you.
코치님..
Coach.
와, 이게모야..
Oh, my God.
토니네요
That's you.
뭔가.음..늠름해보여요
You look so...
dashing.
기수가 되려면 저 정도 늠름함은 기본이지
Yes, "dashing" is a
prerequisite for flag bearers.
분대, 집합.
Squad, fall in.
우로 정렬!
Dress right, dress!
하나 둘!
A-ten hut!
준비.
Ready.
받들어 총!
Port, arms.
One, two, three.
One.
Two.
5시 기상? 그것만해도 죽겠는데,
5:00 a.m. wake-up call,
man, that's bad enough.
밥까지 엉망야
But the food? Come on.
Do you know how much
우리 부모들이 등록금을 얼마나 내는 줄 알아?
our parents are paying
for this place?
한달 안에 때려칠테니까, 두고봐
Took me a month to get
kicked out of my last school.
참을 만큼 참았다고.
Think I'm going
for a personal best.
뚱땡아, 괜찮아?
One, two, three.
Hey,
you doing okay, Piggy?
One, two, three.
야, 너무 무리하지마.
Man, you're all flushed.
그만.
Stop!
Just breathe.
심호흡해봐, 어서.
Come on, man.
뚱땡이, 지금 뭐하는 건가?
Cadet Piggy, what the hell
are you doing?
좀 쉬게 해줘요, 골란
He needs a break,
Golan, come on.
교관이다
That's Drill Leader.
뭐?
What?
교관님이라 부르라고, 디노조 생도.
You will address me
as drill leader, Cadet DiNozzo.
그럽시다, 교관님
Okay, well,
Drill Leader,
뚱땡이는 좀 숴야 됩니다
I think Piggy
needs a little break.
너무 무리했어요
And probably the nurse.
두가지를 시정해라, 디노조
That's two demerits, DiNozzo.
뭔데요?
훈련을 니 마음데로 중단하지 말고,
What for?
One for dropping out of PT.
말투를 고쳐라
One for your tone.
네네, 아무튼, 뚱땡이를 양호실로 보냅시다
Yeah, whatever--
let's get Piggy to the nurse.
뚱땡이는 여기 있을거다
Piggy is gonna stay
where he is until
분대의 일원이 되는 법을 배울때까지.
he learns how to
keep up with the rest
그리고, 너는
of the squad,
and you are gonna
당장 니 자리로 돌아가는게 좋을 거다
get back in line if you
know what's good for you.
좋아요, 한가지는 확실히 합시다
Well, one thing's for sure--
나한테 뭐가 좋은 지는 나도 압니다
I've never known
what's good for me.
제자리에 섯!
Company, halt!
크리스틴이 죽고나서
I called Wallis after
제가 왈리스한테 전화했습니다
Christine died.
그도 알아야 될것 같아서요.
I thought he should know.
왜 그렇게 생각했죠?
Why would he need to know?
우린 교칙위반을 조사하는게 아니라 살인사건을 수사 중야
We're investigating
Wallis's murder,
not an infraction
of the school's code of conduct.
두사람이 사귀고 있었죠?
They were dating,
weren't they?
작년 가을부터 사귀고 있었습니다
It started last year,
after the fall formal,
왈리스가 졸업한 후에도 만났구요
and they stayed together even
after Wallis graduated.
왈리스의 입대 때문에 힘들었겠군요
Must have been hard on Christine
when Wallis enlisted.
잘 견디고 있었다고는 할 수 없죠
I can't say.
She kept it to herself.
왈리스하고는 가까웠나?
You were close
with Wallis?
2년간 제 직속상관이였습니다
He was my commanding
officer for two years.
네, 꽤 친했죠.
Yeah, we were tight.
왈리스가 학교에 온적 있었나요?
없었습니다.
Wallis come back to campus?
No, ma'am.
왈리스는 크리스틴과 헤어진 후
He was pretty broken up
over Christine.
Said he was gonna
정말 슬프고, 가슴 아프다고 말했습니다
drown away his sorrows,
crawl into a hole.
죄송합니다, 제가 아는 건 이게 답니다.
I'm sorry, that's all I know.
그래요...
Well...
다른 게 생각나면, 연락주세요.
call us if you
think of anything else.
디노조 특수요원님
Special Agent DiNozzo.
요원님과 같은 선배를 둬서 영광입니다
It's graduates like you
that make this school proud.
아, 경례 받아주길 원하는거 같은데..
Uh, I think he
wants you to salute
나도 알아
him back.
I know.
고맙다.
이만.
Thank you.
Ma'am.
어쩌면 그가 맞겠네요.
Maybe he's right.
왈리스는 이 꼬인 상황을 스스로 해결하려고 탈영했나 봐요
Wallis went off
to self-medicate,
got caught
in a bad situation.
어떻게 생각해요?
What do you think?
난 말야, 아까부터 우릴 지켜보는 저 놈이 수상한 것 같아
I think the guy
over at that pickup
has been watching us
since we got out here.
어떤 사람요?
What guy?
사라졌군
There was a guy.
몇시간 전에 연락주시기 전까진
Didn't even know
the phone was here
핸드폰이 여기 있는지도 몰랐네요
until I heard it come to
life a few hours ago.
깜짝 놀랐어요
Scared me to death.
왈리스가 왓엇나요?
네.
Wallis came to see you?
Yeah.
탈영한 줄은 몰랐습니다
Didn't know he was UA.
지저분 하죠?
Sorry about the mess.
새로 산 선반 톱이 속 좀 썩이네요
Been having a hell of a time
with this new table saw.
1,500달러 짜린데, 이모양예요
For $1,500,
you think she'd work.
왈리스가 왜 만나러 왔을까요?
Why'd Wallis come to see you?
제가 그의 맨토였거든요
I was his mentor.
그와 동문이세요?
You went to RMA?
학교가 절 구했죠
School saved my life.
남자로 만들어줬으니까요.
Turned me from a punk
into a man.
군 입대와 사업, 모두 학교 덕분이죠
Enlisted in the Corps,
went into business.
All thanks to RMA.
그래서 환원하려구,
So I give back.
장학금을 주고 있어요
Started a scholarship.
캔터 장학금
The Cantor Scholars.
매년 학생을 선발해서 지원하고 있습니다
I pick a different
kid every year.
Pay their way
through RMA.
도와주는거죠
Help 'em out.
왈리스도 장학금을 받았나요?
And Wallis was
one of these kids?
리치몬드의 똥통학교에서 빼왔죠
Got him out of the worst
school in Richmond.
처음 봤을 때부터, 기대가 컸어요
From the day I met him,
I knew he'd do me proud.
그날 밤, 왈리스의 상태는 어땠나요?
What about the night
he came here?
여자친구의 자살 때문에, 엉망이였습니다
He was a mess.
His girlfriend had
committed suicide.
어찌할바를 모르더군요
He didn't know what to do.
제가 좀 다독여줬습니다
I tried to guide him.
왈리스는 죽기 5일전에 탈영했습니다.
Wallis was UA for five days
before he died.
어디로 가려던 걸까요?
Any idea
where he might go?
가족은 아닐겁니다
Not his family.
그가 2학년때 도시를 떠났거든요
They bugged out of town
his sophomore year.
주소도 남기지 않았어요
No forwarding address.
이웃들과도 친하지 않았습니다
He came from a
tough neighborhood.
범죄가 많이 일어나는 지역이였죠
A lot of gang violence.
평생 거길 벗어나려고 싸웠어요
He fought his whole life
to get away.
엄청 노력했을 겁니다
Maybe he didn't have
any fight left in him.
좋아, 이것만은 확실히 해두지
Okay, let's get something
you will not,
오늘 학교에서 본것에 대해 맥기한테는 절대 말하지 마
under any circumstances,
tell McGee
one detail of what you saw
at my old school.
내가 본거라곤, 토니가 좋은 생도였고
The only thing I saw was
that you were a good cadet,
모두가 존경한다는 것 뿐예요
and that they respect you.
그래.. 그러니까 발설하지 마
Yeah... so let's not
go blabbing about it.
뭐가 그렇게 부끄러운데요?
Why does it bother you?
인생의 일부잖아요
It's part of who you are.
과거를 부정해선 안돼요, 토니
You can't ignore
your past, Tony.
그냥 좀 봐달라구
Just watch me.
한마디라도 뻥끗하면,
And not one word
or I'll tell McGee
니가 샤워할때 부른 노래, 맥기한테 다 알려줄테다
that song you sing
in the shower.
그걸 어떻게....?
싸구려 모텔이잖아. 벽도 얇고.
How did...?
Cheap motel. Thin walls.
엄청 못 부르더만
It's a ridiculous song.
좀 더 밞아, 아니면 니가 초대한 저녁식사에 늦겠어
Step on it or we're gonna be
late for this dinner of yours.
어이휴.. 너나 깁스나.
Oh, you and Gibbs.
엄청난 특수요원 디노조입니다.
Very Special Agent DiNozzo.
크리스틴과 왈리스에 대해 아직 모르는게 있습니다.
You don't know the whole story
about Christine and Wallis.
누굽니까?
Who is this?
익명의 협조자죠
Someone who can help.
좋아요, 말씀하세요
Okay. I'm listening.
제가 모르는게 뭘까요?
What don't I know
about Christine and Wallis?
전화론 안돼요, 만납시다
Not on the phone.
We meet in person.
너틀리 하드웨어, 주차장에서.
Parking lot.
Nutley Hardware.
아, 너틀리..
Oh, Nutley.
레밍턴 학교 바로 옆에 있어..음..
That's right next to Remington
Academy. Um...
우린 지금 DC로 복귀하는 중입니다만..
we just got back to DC.
진실을 알고싶다면 돌아오는게 좋을겁니다
You better turn around if you
want to know why Wallis died.
알겠습니다, 6시간 후에 봅시다
All right, we'll be there
in six hours.
주유소에서 파는 타키토 사 갈께요.
We'll bring breakfast.
Hope you like
gas station taquitos.
잘됐네. 한가지 더 남았는데..
All right. Leaves one issue.
아냐, 괜찮아, 사건 때문에
No, I understand,
you have to go back.
돌아가야 된다는 거지?
It's for the case.
응, 당신도 집에 갈 수 있으니까 좋지?
Well, the good news is,
you can go home.
깁스는 걱정하지마, 토니가 연락할거야.
And don't worry about Gibbs.
Tony's gonna let him know.
아, 이미 전화한거 같아.
Oh, I think he
already does.
그래, 알았다, 디노조
Well, yeah, DiNozzo.
잘 처리하고..
You do what you got to do.
미안해
I'm so sorry.
알았어. 그럼 끊을께.
Okay. I'm gonna go now.
우리 둘 뿐인가 보네요
I guess it's just
the two of us.
주문 할까요?
Should we eat?
제이크, 하나만 물어보도록 하지
Jake, I want to ask you
something...
일과 관계된 거네
work-related.
기밀유지가 필요한건가 보네요
Will it require top-secret
clearance to answer?
맞아.
Yeah.
아무한테도 얘기하면 안되네.
듣고 있습니다.
And it stays between us.
I'm all ears.
러시아인과 팔레스타인인의 관계에 대해 아는게 있나?
What do you know about Russian
and Palestinian relations?
Ah.
익명의 제보자가 나타날꺼라 생각해?
You think our Deep Throat's
a no-show?
음?
Hmm?
뭐요?
What?
나타났군..
Who's this?
시작하자..
Here we go.
타요. 그들한테 들킬 수 있어요
Get in. They could
be watching us.
"그들" 요?
"They" would be...?
뚱땡이? 너냐?
Piggy? Is that you?
이젠 그렇게 부르는 사람 없어, 토니.
Nobody calls me that
anymore, Tony.
빨리 타요. 여긴 위험해요.
Now get in the truck.
It's not safe.
여긴 어디예요?
What is this place?
무슨, 폐기물 창고예요?
Some kind of
condemned property?
제 집입니다.
It's my house.
아, 죄송해요, 그게..음..
Oh. Sorry. It's, uh...
좀 특이하군요
It's very distinct.
야, 그거 꺼!
Hey, turn that off!
괜찮아, 뭐가 무서운건데, 트래비스?
No. What are you
afraid of, Travis?
학교야, 토니.
RMA, Tony.
우릴 항상 감시한다고.
They're everywhere.
학교를 두려워하는 이유가 뭐죠?
Why are you afraid of RMA?
제가 그들을 위해 일했거든요
Because I work for them.
좋아.. 아까 왈리스와 크리스틴에게
Okay... you said
you knew what happened
무슨 일이 생긴건지 안다고 했지?
with Wallis and Christine.
크리스틴의 죽음은 니가 아는 그런게 아냐
Christine's death
is not what you think.
자살한게 아닌가요?
She didn't commit suicide?
그렇게 되도록 몰아넣은 겁니다.
She was pushed to it.
명예부대였어요
It was Honor Corps.
누구야?
Hello?
뭐하는 거야?
What the hell?
왜들이래?
디노조 생도.
- What's up, guys?
- Cadet DiNozzo.
교내 행동수칙 위반에 대해 유죄를 선고한다.
You've been found guilty
of breaking rules
of the code of conduct.
처벌은 명예부대가 실시한다.
Your punishment will be
delivered by Honor Corps.
니들이 명예부대인 모양이군
I'm guessing
you're the Honor Corps.
밤새도록 괴롭혀주지, 디노조
You're ours for
the night, DiNozzo,
재밌을거다..
and we're gonna have fun.
그래, 맘데로 해라, 난 빠질테니까..
Yeah, I'm gonna go ahead
and opt out.
음..안돼지..
Mm... no.
좋아, 정말 해보고 싶냐?
All right, you really want
to do this?
그래?
Huh?
디노조, 여기서 뭐하는 거냐?
DiNozzo, where
the hell have you been?
농구 연습은 10분전에 시작됐다
Basketball practice
started ten minutes ago
헬스실로 내려와, 빨리..
down in the weight room--
you're late.
쟤는 빼고 니들끼리 해라
Need to make do without him.
고마워요, 테너 코치님.
아직 고마워하긴 이르지.
Thanks, Coach Tanner.
Don't thank me yet.
슛하는걸 봤다. 재능이 있더구나
I've seen you shoot.
You got talent.
농구팀에 가입한걸 축하한다.
I meant it-- you're officially
on the basketball team,
공식적으로 10분 지각이다.
and officially
ten minutes late.
20바퀴 돌아, 디노조.
20 laps, DiNozzo.
태너 코치가 명예부대를 없앤 뒤론 괜찮았잖아
I thought
Coach Tanner put an end
to Honor Corps our senior year.
없어진게 아냐
Nothing ended senior year.
더 은밀해졌을 뿐이지
They just kept
it quieter.
그리고, 농수선수들은 건들지도 않았고..
And basketball players
were off-limits.
내가 명예부대 놈들에게
You have no idea what
was happening to me
무슨 짓을 당했는지, 넌 상상도 못할거야
when Honor Corps came around.
명예부대란게 뭐죠?
What's Honor Corps?
학생들을 괴롭히는 수준낮은 생도들의 모임입니다
It's a group of students
who bully substandard cadets.
규칙위반자나 열등한 생도들을 골라 괴롭혔죠.
Break a rule, or bring
squad performance down,
and they pay you a visit.
Look...
트래비스..
Travis...
당신이 겪은 일은 정말 유감입니다. 근데..
I'm sorry for what happened
to you, but...
크리스틴은 어떻게 된거죠?
I'm wondering
what happened to Christine.
그놈들이 처벌한 겁니다.
They disciplined her.
죽기 전 한달동안, 매일밤마다 괴롭혔죠
Every night for a month
before she died.
놈들이 헤친겁니다
They broke her.
근데, 왈리스는 어떻게 안걸까요?
So, how does Wallis play
into all this?
제가 얘기했습니다.
I told him exactly
what I told you.
왈리스가 왔었어?
Wallis was here?
크리스틴이 죽고나서, 며칠 후에 왔어
He came a few days
after Christine died.
어떻게 된건지 알고 싶어하더군
He was looking for answers.
여기로 데려와서, 모든 걸 말해줬어
I brought him here, and
I told him everything.
그걸 듣고는 학교로 돌아가 명예부대 놈들과 싸웠지
Then he went back to campus
to confront Honor Corps.
누구와 싸웠나요?
Who did he confront?
저도 얼굴이나 이름은 몰라요
I don't know their names
or faces,
근데, 왈리스는 어느 놈인지 아는 것처럼 보였어요
but Wallis sure seemed to know
whose ass he was going to kick.
이봐, 트레비스...
Listen, Travis...
미안해..
I am sorry.
그땐 정말 니가 무슨 일을 겪고 있는지 몰랐어
I had no idea what was
happening to you back then.
관심도 없었잖아
'Cause you never asked.
캔터의 말한것처럼, 왈리스의 죽음이
Well, I spent the morning
trying to find out
if Wallis's death was
gang-related,
주변 갱들과 관계된 건지 조사해봤는데
like Frederick Cantor suggested.
문제 한번 일으키지 않은 모범생이더군
Turns out
he was a straight-A student,
never got into any trouble.
또 다른건, 애비가
Now, on the plus side,
학교 근처 버스정류장의 감시카메라를 분석했는데
Abby managed to get surveillance
from the bus station near RMA,
며칠전, 왈리스가 학교에 온게 확실해
was able to prove
that Wallis was
at the school a few days ago.
멋진데요, 맥기. 근데..
That's great, McGee. Hey...
지난밤 저녁식사는 어땠어요?
I need to know what happened
at dinner last night.
오, 아..그게..
Oh, uh...
깁스와 제이크, 둘이
Well, last I saw, Gibbs and Jake
were at the table.
같이 있는거까지보고 난 나왔어.
I didn't stick around.
둘만 내버려두면 어떡해요?
Why did you leave them alone?
자기들끼리 알아서하는거지 모.
It was every man for himself.
왜? 제이크가 뭐라고 해?
Why? What did Jake say?
그이한테 들은건 아니고..
Well, I haven't heard from him.
알았어요, 제이크와 통화할께요
All right, I'm calling Jake
again right now.
그래.
Okay.
여보세요?
맥기?
- Hello?
- McGee?
제이크한테 걸었는데..
I was trying
to call Jake's phone.
그건 맞는데, 전화가 깁스 책상에 있네
You did call Jake's phone.
It was on Gibbs' desk.
왜 그이 핸드폰이 깁스 책상에 있어요?
Why is my husband's phone
on Gibbs' desk?
핸드폰엔 왜 "엘리 벨리" 라고 등록돼 있는거야?
Hey, why does he call you
"Ellie Belly"?
팀, 농담아녜요
Tim, this is serious.
팀?
Tim?
있잖아, 내가 다시 걸께..
You know what?
I'm gonna call you back.
아니, 잠깐. 팀?
No, wait. Tim...?
안녕하십니까, 보스.
Hey, boss.
What's up?
아침에 실버 스프링에 다녀왔는데 말야,
I was in Silver Springs
this morning--
크리스틴 샌더스가 어디 출신인지 알아?
where Christine
Sanders is from?
겨울방학때 경찰에 신고한 사건이 있더군
She filed a police report
over winter break.
스토킹 당했나요?
She was being stalked?
누군가 상점부터 미행해서
Someone followed
her at the mall.
밤에 그녀의 집을 침입했다더군
And then, he was in
her house at night.
그녀도 아는 사람이라지, 아마..
Someone she knew.
전 스토커가 아닙니다
그럼, 겨울방학때
- I'm not a stalker.
- How do you explain
크리스틴 집엔 왜 따라갔는데?
following Christine home
for winter break?
우린 친구였어요
We were friends.
친구는 남의 침실에 몰래 침입해서
Friends don't
sneak into each other's
깜짝 놀래키는 짓 따윈 하지 않아요
bedrooms to surprise them.
전 선임생도에, 풋볼팀 주장입니다.
I'm Senior Cadet,
captain of the football team,
그녀가 원하는 줄 알고 찾아간 거라구요
and I haven't got there
by taking no for an answer.
You have no clue
그런식으로 함부로 말하지 말아요
how bad that sounds, do you?
경찰이 체포하자 그때서야 알았습니다
I got the message
when the police cuffed me,
그리고 유치장에 갔죠
and they threw me
in a holding cell.
그 후론 건들지 않았어요
I left her alone
after that.
아니지..
No, you didn't.
크리스틴에게 벌을 주러 간거잖아
You wanted
to punish Christine.
아닙니다, 전 건들지 않았어요
No... no, I didn't touch her.
그렇겠죠.
Right.
명예부대가 했으니까.
아, 명예부대....
- Honor Corps did.
- Ah...
그건 그저 신입생들에게 겁을 주기 위한
Honor Corps is a folk tale
that we tell plebes
장난일 뿐입니다.
저기, 이봐요..
to scare them--
Hey... hey!
거긴 들어가면 안돼요
You can't go in there.
나도 여기 출신이다, 크레이그 생도.
I went to this school,
Cadet Craig.
이 완장이 뭔지 안다구.
I know what a gray
armband means.
당신은 명예부대를 이용해서
You used Honor Corps
크리스틴에게 거절당한 보복을 했던 거예요
to punish Christine
for turning you down.
그런게 아녜요
It's not like that.
그게 아니라고? 그럼 뭔데?
It's not like that?
What's it like?
한밤중에 그녀를 밖으로 끌어내서,
You'd drag her out at night,
모욕하고, 굴리려고 한건가?
force her to do PT,
humiliate herself.
우리도 행동규칙이 있습니다
We have a code of conduct.
규칙을 위반하면, 댓가를 치뤄야죠.
You break the code,
you pay the price.
크리스틴은 규칙을 어겼어요
그말은 결국,
Christine broke the code.
Translation being:
그녀를 괴롭히려고 얘기를 꾸몄다는 거군
you made up a reason
to get her in trouble.
너같은 녀석들을 겪어봤다
I remember guys like you.
어떤 무리의 일원이 되는데 급급해서
Drank the Kool-Aid,
believed in the traditions,
악습도 전통이라고 무조건 믿어버리지
because you were desperate
to be a part of something.
근데, 이건 알아둬
Well, guess what?
그 무리의 일원은 됐을지 몰라도,
You're part of something.
세상이란 곳은 말야, 생도,
But outside
of these walls, Cadet,
규칙따위에는 아무 관심도 없다구.
nobody gives a damn
about your code.
당신이 크리스틴을 죽음으로 몰아넣은 거예요
Whatever you did
led Christine to kill herself.
증명하지 못할 겁니다.
그럴 필요 없어요
You can't prove that.
We don't have to.
크리스틴 때문에 당신을 체포하러 온건 아니니까.
We're not here to arrest you
for Christine's suicide.
왈리스의 살인사건 때문이지..
Wallis's murder,
on the other hand...
왈리스가 명예부대를 찾으러
- I, uh...
- We know he came to campus,
학교로 간건 알아요. 당신에게 왔겠죠
found out about Honor Corps,
and he came looking for you.
넌 선임생도에,
You are the senior cadet,
captain of the football team,
풋볼팀 주장야.
with a bright future
ahead of you.
미래가 창창하지..
근데 어떻게 될까?
Unless it disappears.
어떻게 된건지 말해
Tell us what happened.
왈리스가 당신을 보러왔죠
Wallis came to see you.
엄청 화났더군요
He was furious.
그럴만도 했죠.
He had every right to be. I...
제가 크리스틴을 너무 몰아댔어요,
I pushed Christine too far,
and, uh...
자살하게 만든거죠
...I made her kill herself.
그 댓가를 치루길 원하더군요
And he wanted to make me pay.
싸웠나요?
You fought him?
아뇨.
No.
테너 교장님이 말렸어요
Provost Tanner stopped him.
사건현장의 타이어 자국과
I finally got a hit
똑같은 걸 드디어 찾았어요
on the tire tracks
from your crime scene.
모, 쉽진 않았어요.. 현재 팔리는
And it wasn't easy, either.
I compared them to every tire
모든 타이어와 비교해봤는데
that's actively sold
on the market.
없었어요. 그래서,
No match.
Then I compared them
전 세계를 다 뒤졌어요.
to international tires.
없더군요, 그래서 머리 좀 굴려봤죠.
Nothing, so I had to
think out of the box.
생산 중단된 타이어.
Discontinued tires.
딱 맞췄답니다.
And that's when I hit pay dirt.
이 바퀴자국은 70년대 유럽차에 많이 쓰던 거예요
The track is from a tread used
exclusively in the 1970s
on various European cars.
70년대 생산된 타이어가 아직도 사용 가능하다구?
Could a tire
manufactured in the '70s
still be operational today?
아니, 근데, 복제품이 있지요
No, but a replica could.
이건 주문생산 된건데, 원래 타이어는,
This is a custom job
made to resemble
the original tire of...
72년형 씨트로엥 DS에 쓰였어요
a 1972 Citroen DS.
디노조
DiNozzo!
방금 크레이그 생도의 부친에게 항의전화 받았어
I just got a very angry call
from Cadet Craig's father.
나한테 알리지도 않고 우리 학생을 취조하면 안돼네
You can't be
interrogating
one of my students
without letting me know.
근데, 내 차는 왜 살피는 건가?
And why are you looking
at my car?
코치님, 트렁크 좀 열어주시겟습니까?
Coach, will you open
the trunk, please?
아니면, 영장을 받아서 부술까요?
Or I'll get a warrant
and break it open.
감사합니다.
Thank you.
옆으로 비키시죠
Please step to the side.
엄청난 혈흔이네요
There was a lot of
blood back here.
제럴드 테너씨,
Gerald Tanner,
당신을 존 왈리스 살해혐의로 체포합니다.
you are under arrest
for the murder of John Wallis.
아, 좀.
Come on. Come on.
젠장!
Damn!
그래서 계획이 뭐냐?
What's the plan here?
내차 훔쳐서 멕시코로 가려구?
Steal the coach's car,
drive to Mexico?
모, 그럴수도 있죠.
Hey, maybe.
전 여기와 안맞아요
I don't belong here.
이런 딱딱한 생활과는 거리가 멀죠
I'm not a
rules-and-regulations guy.
그래서 아버님이 널 7번째 학교로 보내셨겠지
So your dad sends you
to school number seven.
그래도 이렇게 도망치는 건 아닌것 같다
It don't feel right.
You cut and run.
그게 얼마나 가겠냐?
But for how long?
여긴 기회가 있어
You have
an opportunity here.
넌 농구에 재능도 있고 말야.
You have talent
on the basketball court.
똑똑하잖아.
You're smart.
딱딱한 생활이 싫다고?
You don't like rules
and regulations?
나도, 마찬가지야
Me, neither.
그것 때문에 자신을 망치겠다고?
You gonna let that
stop you?
자기방어죠.
It's self-preservation.
골란 생도때문에 걱정되냐?
날 미워해요.
You're worried about Cadet Golan?
He hates me.
명예부대도 있구요.
And he runs Honor Corps.
당하는건 시간 문제예요.
It's only a matter of time.
명예부대 애들은 널 건들지 못한다.
Honor Corps won't touch you.
어떻게 장담하세요?
How do you know that?
농구부에 가입했잖아, 디노조.
Because you're a starter
on the varsity basketball team, DiNozzo...
내 팀원들은 내가 챙긴다.
and I look out for my guys.
이제, 학교 안의 많은 것들이 변할거다
Now, there are things
about this school
that are gonna change.
명예부대도 마찬가지고.
여긴 괜찮은 곳이야.
Honor Corps is one of them.
This is a good place.
니가 있을만한 곳이고.
You do belong.
도망치지 말고,
Don't run.
버텨라.
Take a stand.
내가 함께 있어 주마
And I'll stand with you.
그는 제 맨토 였어요
He was a mentor.
대신 해줄까?
Want me to take
the interview?
아뇨, 전 피하지 않습니다.
No. I'm not gonna run.
얼마나 멋진 상황인지 아실겁니다.
You had a nice long car ride
to think
그러니 잘 생각하고 말하세요
about what you're gonna say,
변명도 하지 마시구요
so don't make
any excuses.
그저 설명만 해주시면 됩니다
I want an explanation.
학교에서 왈리스를 만나지 못했다고 거짓말 하셨습니다
You lied to me about seeing
Wallis on campus that night.
왈리스에 대해 얘기할 수 없었네. 왜냐하면.....
왜냐하면, 차 트렁크 안에
I didn't tell you about Wallis because...
Because his blood
왈리스의 피가 잔뜩 묻어서겠죠.
was all over the trunk
of your car?
어떻게 된일인지 모르겠네
I don't know how that got there.
왜 내가 죽였다고 생각하지?
Why would I kill Wallis?
명예부대.
Honor Corps.
분명 20년전에 해체시켰다고 말씀하셨어요
You said you were gonna get
rid of that 20 years ago.
그랬으면 했지
Wanted to.
쉬운일이 아니였네
It's not that easy.
우리 학교의 전통을 알잖는가
You know how RMA is
with tradition.
명예부대 따위는 전통이 아닙니다.
Honor Corps is not
a tradition.
기수단이나 신입생 주간처럼, 우리의 뼛속까지 스며있었어.
It is as ingrained
in our DNA
as Color Guard or Plebe Week.
You're the provost.
당신이 교장입니다.
교장만의 노력으로 바꿀 수 있는게 아니네, 토니
I didn't get to be provost
by effecting change, Tony.
왈리스와 만난 밤, 무슨일이 있었습니까?
What happened the night
Wallis confronted you?
크레이그와 치고박는 걸 말려서,
I stopped him
from pummeling Craig.
사무실로 데려왔지
Took him
to my office.
크리스틴의 죽음이 명예부대 때문이라고..
He blamed Honor Corps
for Christine's death.
이 참에 낱낱이 밝히겠다고 하더군.
Wanted to shine a light.
명예부대를 폭로하는 건 결국,
I told him that if he exposed
Honor Corps that...
학교에 피해를 입히는 거라고 말해줫네.
it would hurt the school.
적어도, 뭐가 더 중요한지는 아시는 분이잖아요.
At least you had your
priorities straight.
여기서 그만해야, 해결할 수 있다고 말해줬어
I told Wallis that he needed
to take a step back, that...
we could work it out.
믿지 않았겠죠..
But he could tell
you were lying.
지난 수년간, 우리 학교가
You know how many kids
얼마나 많은 학생을 구제했는지 아니?
this school has saved,
over the years?
너를 봐.
Just like you?
큰 성공을 위해서라면 낙오자 몇명은 감수해야 하는거 아닌가?
Doesn't that success outweigh
a few lost causes?
크리스틴은 낙오자가 아닙니다.
Christine wasn't a lost cause--
그들은 낙오자가 아녜요. 그저 도움이 필요한 학생일 뿐입니다.
none of 'em were-- they were
just kids who needed help.
저처럼요.
Just like me.
언제 칼로 찌르셨죠?
When did you pull the knife?
내 얘길 듣지 않는군, 디노조
You're not listening, DiNozzo.
난 찌르지 않았네
I didn't touch him.
그는 폭로하겠다면서, 사무실을 나갔네
He walked out of my office,
prepared to expose us.
난 그걸 걱정했고...
I braced myself
for the fallout.
트렁크에 묻은 피는 어떻게 된겁니까?
How did his blood get
in your car?
잘 모르겠네. 그 차는 거의 고장난 상태야
I don't know.
I-I barely drive the car.
대부분 카센터에 있었어.
카센터 없던 때는 언젠데요?
Spends most of the time in the shop.
And when it's not in the shop?
항상 거기에 있었어
It is where it always is.
보조열쇠가 어딨는지는 다 알고 있고..
And everybody knows
where I keep the spare key.
그래도 결국 떠나기로 했다면,
If you change your mind
and decide to leave...
이걸 사용하는게 좋을거야
...don't hot-wire my car.
나를 뭐라 생각해도 상관없지만, 절대 내가 한짓이 아니다
Whatever you think of me,
I never could have done this.
오래전이지만, 아직도 학교에 대해 말하지 않아요
I left RMA a long time ago.
I don't talk about it.
그건 제가 아니였거든요
It's not who I am.
근데, 이건 아직도 기억납니다.
But there was a part of me
that still believed.
모토, 규칙..
In the motto. The code.
이제 그것마저 사라졌네요
And that part's gone now...
크리스틴 센더스,
along with Christine Sanders...
존 왈리스와 함께..
and John Wallis.
토니가 맞았네요
Tony was right.
보조키가 햇빛가리개 안에 있었어요
The spare key
was in the sun visor.
운전대와 변속기엔 왈리스의 지문이 잔뜩 찍혀있구요.
And Wallis's prints are all over
the steering wheel
왈리스가 태너의 차를 가져갔고,
- and the gear shift.
- Wallis took Tanner's car,
범인이 다시 갖다 논 거네요
and Wallis's killer
brought the car back to RMA.
다른 지문은?
Any other fingerprints?
아뇨, 다른 건 없어요
No. There were
no more fingerprints or DNA.
근데, 파라핀 왁스의 흔적을 발견했어요
But I did find traces
of paraffin wax.
태너가 목수였나?
Was Tanner a carpenter?
버스정류장 감시카메라에 접속 가능한가?
We have access to the bus
station security cameras?
네.
Yes.
왈리스가 죽은 후
I want to see the 24-hour period
24시간 동안의 녹화기록을 보여줘
after Wallis was killed.
왈리스가 죽은 후요?
After Wallis was killed?
집에 태너의 차를 갖다 놓으려면 거길 반드시 지나야 하는구나.
Whoever returned Tanner's car
needed a way to get home.
깁스요원님.
Special Agent Gibbs.
노크 소리를 못들었습니다만..
Didn't hear you knock.
안했습니다.
I didn't.
이 빌어먹을 톱이 아직도 말썽을 부려서요
Still having trouble
with this damn saw.
작동하질 않네요
Just won't work right.
안에 뭔가 묻은거 같은데..
Something got in here
that wasn't supposed to.
제 생각엔, 존 왈리스의 피 같군요.
I'm guessing
it's John Wallis's blood.
그가 당신을 다시 찾아왔죠
He came down here again,
to see you.
학교 근처 버스정류장에 설치된
We have
surveillance footage
감시카메라의 영상을 확인했습니다
of you from the bus station
near RMA.
멈춰.
Stop.
문제가 생기는 걸 그냥 볼 수 없었어요
I'm not gonna
cause you any problems.
결국 다시 올줄 알았죠
I knew you'd come back
to me eventually.
끌에서 왈리스의 피를 찾을 수 있을 겁니다.
You'll find Wallis's blood
on the chisel.
깨끗하게 닦으려 했는데..
압니다,
I tried to clean up, but...
Yeah.
피를 깨끗하게 닦는건 쉬운일이 아니죠.
Blood doesn't clean up
too easy, does it?
왈리스가 돌아왔을 때 무슨일이 있었던 겁니까?
What happened when
Wallis came back here?
흥분했더군요
He was upset.
명예부대에 대해 막말을하고, 학교를 청소하겠다고 했어요
He was talking wildly about
Honor Corps and cleaning up RMA.
언론사에 폭로하길 원하더군요
He wanted to go public.
명예부대의 출발점을 몰랐던 겁니다.
He didn't know
where to start.
도움이 필요했던 겁니다.
He needed your help.
어떤 파문이 생길지 이해하지 못하더군요
He didn't understand
the ramifications.
그런 스캔들은 학교명성에 먹칠을 하는겁니다.
A scandal like this
could hobble the school.
난 아내도, 자식도 없어요. 학교가 내 모든것입니다
I have no wife, no kids--
all I have is RMA.
내 유일한 유산이죠
It's my legacy.
왈리스가 그걸 망치게 내버려둘 순 없었어요
I couldn't have let
Wallis threaten that.
이미 망가졌는데도요?
Even if your legacy is broken?
당신 눈엔 명예부대가 부당한 것처럼 보이겠지만, 꽤 효과적입니다.
Honor Corps seems harsh
to an outsider, but it works.
잡초를 속아내는 거죠
Weeds out the weak.
거기서 살아남은 젊은이들이 표본이 되는 거죠
Challenges the rest
to live up to a standard.
남자가 되는 거예요
It made a man out of me.
그렇습니까?
Did it?
남잔, 뭐가 중요한지 알아야 철이드는 거예요
Man enough to know
what's important.
전통에 대한 존중.
To respect tradition.
진실, 용기, 책임
"Truth, Valor, Duty."
그게 우리 모토란 말입니다.
That's our motto.
기회를 줬는데도, 왈리스가 배신한거예요
I gave it to Wallis,
and he betrayed it.
아뇨, 충실히 따랐을 뿐입니다
No, he lived up to the motto.
배신한건 당신이죠
You betrayed him.
날 풀어줬네
They're letting me go.
이건 꼭 말해주고 싶었는데, 난 말야..음..
Uh, I just wanted to say
that I never m...
사직했다
I'm resigning.
니가 맞아. 애들과 너를 실망시켰구나..
You were right-- I let the
kids down, I let you down.
근데, 이것만은 알아둬라
For what it's worth,
지금 니 모습이 난 정말 자랑스럽다
I am proud of the man
you've become.
괜찮아요?
You okay?
당연하지.
Never better.
요런게 있는데 말이죠..
I have something for you.
정말 잘나온 사진인데..
It's a photo of
a photo but...
선배 가져요..
you should keep it.
그냥 과거일 뿐야, 비숍
It's the past, Bishop.
당신의 과거죠, 토니
It's your past, Tony,
좋은 추억이고..
and it's a good one.
과거란게 참 처치곤란한 존재야
I have a tricky relationship
with the past.
묻어버리지도 못하고,
I either bury it...
바꾸지도 못하고..
or fixate on it.
여전히 골치거리니까 말야.
Still working out the kinks.
뭐.. 무슨일을 겪어던 간에..
Well... whatever
happened in your past,
그게 당신을 지금처럼 멋진 남자로 만든거예요
helped make you the
awesome guy you are today.
와, 제이크 말로이 아냐?
Well, if it isn't
Jake Molloy!
어쩐 일이신가~
Look at you!
안녕.
Hey.
응..
어딨었어?
응, 미안, 미안..
Where were you?
Yeah, I'm-I'm, I'm sorry.
하루종일 NAS에 중요한 회의가 있었거든
Closed-door meetings
at NSA all day long.
전화도 못했어, 어..
I mean, I would've
called but, uh--
깁스가 핸드폰을 가져가서?
응.
But Gibbs had your phone?
Yeah.
어제밤에 식당에 놔두고 왔거든..
I left it in the diner
last night.
여기 뒀다고, 가져가라더군
He said he'd leave it here
and I could pick it up.
미안해, 저녁식사에 못가서..
Sorry I made you
sit through dinner.
오, 아냐, 괜찮아
Oh, no, don't be.
꽤 괜찮았어
It was great.
생각보단 대화하기 편하던데 모..
I mean, Gibbs is
so easy to talk to.
진짜요?
He is?
네, 맞아요.
Yeah, yeah.
좋은 얘길 많이 나눴어요
And we had a lot to discuss.
어떤 얘기?
Like what?
식사 때 일어난 일은 발설하지 않는게 좋은 법!
What happens in the diner
stays in the diner.
장난하지 말고..
Are you kidding?
무슨 일이 있었는지 자세히 얘기해달라고..
The whole point
of the dinner
was we would have
more to talk about.
어젯밤 얘기는 이걸로 그만하는게 좋겠어
And we will,
just not about last night.
들어보니까,
Well, it sounds like
집에 가는 동안 둘이 할 얘긴 많겠구나.
you guys have a lot to talk
about on the ride home,
잘해봐..
so good luck with that.
네, 꼭 들을거예요
Yes, we will.
담에 봐요, 토니.
Next time, Tony.
내일봐요, 토니.
Bye, Tony.
Hello?
어이, 뚱땡이.
Piggy. Hey.
아, 미안, 트래비스..
I mean, Travis. Sorry.
나야, 토니. 디노조.
It's Tony. DiNozzo.
Oh, hey...
응.
Yeah.
생각해봤는데 말야,
I was thinking, what do you say
식사 전이면, 밥이나 같이 먹자구, 어때?
we grab a late dinner, catch up?
중간쯤에서 보면 되겠는데 말야
I can meet you halfway.
파섹에서, 어때?
How about Passaic?
Sure...
3시간 쯤 걸려..
Three hours.
이따보자.
I'll see you there.
All right.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
발자막 보시느라, 고생요..
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man